To create an effective text
prompt for text-to-speech,
TTS, it's important to use
clear and concise language
that mimics natural speech
patterns. Structure your
sentences in a way that allows
for smooth intonation and
pacing. Avoid overly complex
sentences or jargon that might
confuse the TTS engine. Use
punctuation strategically,
commas, periods, and question
marks, help guide the rhythm
of speech. If you need to
emphasize certain words,
consider using capitalization
or punctuation like dashes or
ellipses for pauses. Lastly,
ensure that the text is free
from spelling errors or
abbreviations that could be
mispronounced. By following
these tips, you'll enhance the
clarity and natural flow of
the speech output.